<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Matt McNaughton&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Matt McNaughton&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 09:41:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjmcnaughton.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Contributing to Popular Open-Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/getting-started-contributing-to-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 09:41:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/getting-started-contributing-to-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Few programming experiences are more informative or rewarding than meaningfully contributing to open-source software. However, even programmers with strong technical skills can experience discouragingly high barriers to entry when contributing to a new project. This barrier to entry feels particularly high for the popular, high-velocity projects. Unfortunately, these projects are often those which first catch the eye, and attract us to open source. Overwhelming. Perhaps Steve Harvey shows it best&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming with OCD</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/programming-with-ocd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 09:41:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/programming-with-ocd/</guid>
      <description>Like over 3 million Americans, I struggle with OCD. OCD has impacted, and probably always will in some capacity impact, my life a lot. Unfortunately, software engineering, both my career and one of my favorite hobbies, is no exception.
What is OCD? via GIPHY
Everyone who suffers from OCD has a different experience. For me, OCD manifests as certain distorted thoughts sticking in my brain. These sticky thoughts are typically catastrophic events touching on some of my deepest fears and most cherished values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitting the Ground Running</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/hitting-the-ground-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 02:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/hitting-the-ground-running/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of working at Flatiron Health since August 2016. Some of the biggest lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned have related to participating in effective code reviews. I wrote up some of my learnings in a blog post for Flatiron&amp;rsquo;s Engineering Blog. Hope you enjoy (and check out some of the other great content written by other Flatiron engineers on the blog)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Auto-scaling in Kubernetes - Thesis</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/predictive-auto-scaling-in-kubernetes-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 02:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/predictive-auto-scaling-in-kubernetes-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of my final year at Williams College, I spent a lot of time working on a distributed systems thesis with Professor Jeannie Albrecht. My thesis is entitled &amp;ldquo;Predictive Pod Auto-scaling in the Kubernetes Container Cluster Manager&amp;rdquo;, and it is entirely open-source. The written portion, presentation slides, and evaluation code can be found on my Github. Additionally, our contributions to Google&amp;rsquo;s open-source cluster container manager Kubernetes can be found on my fork.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>