<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essays on ~/mattjmcnaughton/blog</title>
    <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/categories/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essays on ~/mattjmcnaughton/blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mattjmcnaughton.com/categories/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look at Rsync</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/papers-i-love-rsync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/papers-i-love-rsync/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not often that academia analyzes the unix tools we use everyday. But rsync is one fortunate exception as Andrew Tridgell not only wrote rsync while pursuing his PhD, but also published a short and accessible paper outlining its inner workings. While I&amp;rsquo;d highly encourage reading the entire paper, I took away one major tl:dr; from the rsync algorithm: be lazy. This lesson will be applicable anytime I write performance conscious code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Contributing to Popular Open-Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/getting-started-contributing-to-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/getting-started-contributing-to-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>Few programming experiences are more informative or rewarding than meaningfully contributing to open-source software. However, even programmers with strong technical skills can experience discouragingly high barriers to entry when contributing to a new project. This barrier to entry feels particularly high for the popular, high-velocity projects. Unfortunately, these projects are often those which first catch the eye, and attract us to open source. Overwhelming. Perhaps Steve Harvey shows it best&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming with OCD</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/programming-with-ocd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/programming-with-ocd/</guid>
      <description>Like over 3 million Americans, I struggle with OCD. OCD has impacted, and probably always will in some capacity impact, my life a lot. Unfortunately, software engineering, both my career and one of my favorite hobbies, is no exception.
What is OCD? via GIPHY
Everyone who suffers from OCD has a different experience. For me, OCD manifests as certain distorted thoughts sticking in my brain. These sticky thoughts are typically catastrophic events touching on some of my deepest fears and most cherished values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to a Platform for Change</title>
      <link>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/contributing-to-a-platform-for-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjmcnaughton.com/post/contributing-to-a-platform-for-change/</guid>
      <description>Like many others, I’ve spent the last couple of weeks since the election thinking a lot about new ways to empower and amplify all the voices fighting for justice. While it’s not easy to know what to do in a situation like the one we find ourselves in, I’m reminded of words from Bryan Stevenson, a civil rights lawyer, who spoke at my graduation back in June. His entire speech was insightful and inspiring, and one particular request stuck with me: get proximate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
